So, hello everyone welcome back to this video, so now we are going to implement this token
generator function here inside of our auth controller.js, okay.
So as we have already know that we have already has the password and we are using this declaration
as const new user equal to we are creating a new user with the user name email and the password
which we are getting from the request.body, okay.
So now we have also saved the user, so await new user dot save.
So now what we are going to do is like suppose if the new user exists, so we are going
to write the logic as like if the new user is existing.
Then in that case what we are going to do is, in that case we are going to use that token
generation function and so we have imported it here.
So we will have two IDs, two arguments, so a new user dot underscore ID and then a desert response
and after this what we are going to parse is that rs dot JSON response and instead of JSON
response we are going to just pass this new user, okay.
So we are going to pass that detail here and now what we are going to do is we are going
to cache the error.
So inside of this cache block, so we are going to write as console dot log if some error
is found, so error in sign up, so error in sign up and we are going to just pass the error
message, so error dot message, alright.
Now we are going to just say that st status code of 500, so 500 dot JSON, so let us pass
the message in JSON format, so message internal server error, okay.
So now we have done it, so now what we will do is, so this is kind of a POST request
right.
When we hit the button we will be having this POST request, so let us go to this app.js.
I think this one is on controller token.js, user model.js routes, okay.
So this is not a get request, this is a POST request, okay.
So we are going to just change from get to POST request, okay.
So now what we will do is, let us go back to the app.js file and we are going to implement
some middle out functionalities there also.
So what will you do is actually this POST method, okay.
So now after this, since we are passing the data right, so in the passing the data we are
going to use one thing, like one middleware, so instead of the app.js file we are going
to just implement app.use, express.json, okay.
So express.json, so the data is coming in the JSON format, that is why.
And also one thing, go to this auth route.js, so this is also not a get request, it is
a POST request, okay.
So POST request.
So now we are going to test these routes, okay.
So whether they are working or not, so for that we are going to use one tool, which is
an API testing tool, which is called as Postman, okay.
So Postman, so we can open this Postman in order to test our routes.
So let it open after something, I am going to just configure that, it takes a quite a while.
So now append that.
So as you can see that this is the interface of Postman, so what you can actually do is
like go to this workspace here and you can create your newer space.
So if you create newer space it will appear like this.
And now what will we actually be doing, don't save this, like you can go here and create
a one new collection.
So if you click on this create new collection, you can just name this one, okay.
So I have named this as new collection, so we can rename it, we are working authentication
right, like authenticating users to sign in and sign up.
So like that kind of functionality we are going to implement.
So what we are going to do is that we are going to create a new request, okay.
So remove this, okay, remove this one and also here this, if it is present.
So now this is a, let's assign is a post request, okay.
So we are going to just use the data like for the backend, which site we are using.
So we are using the local host 5000, right.
So localhost 5000 and API and then what we are going to do, or slash sign up, we are
going to test the route for the sign up, okay.
So once you do this take here, like click here and assign this a post request.
And now after this what you are going to do is go here in the like JSON and you are going
to pass this in the JSON format, okay.
So you can click here JSON and these double braces will appear.
Instead of that, what are the fields you are going to pass?
So username, right username.
So suppose you are passing as Chantano1 and suppose the email.
So the email would be suppose I am going to take my email.
So like this.
You know how it's coming, we have already made those fields right username, email and passwords.
And now we are just testing that route, particular route.
So we are going to pass the data, I told you, right, that we are going to pass the data.
The user is going to pass the data from the backend, like his username, email and the
password so that it gets a story in the database.
And that's how we are testing it via this tool, which is postman tool, okay.
So how it's working?
And that is a part of API testing.
So now suppose the password will be passed word one, two, three.
So six letters at least it should be right.
So now if you just hit on this, so is some connection request, we will look in it, okay.
So I found out this, actually what is happening here is that I haven't started the backend,
okay.
So let's go to this folder, like in the terminal, you go and then go to this CD into
the backend folder, CD backend and then NPM start using the script NPM start script.
So it is going to start the backend application.
And now once it has started the backend application, as you can see, here's some error.
And why it is actually coming, I will tell you why?
Because when you're logging into the MongoDB database, okay.
So you should have, you have to make that whitelist the IP address again and again.
So it's got some kind of a common error that happens.
So please make sure you log in it, like logging into the MongoDB database and
you just whitelist to the address or allow access from anywhere from like IP address 0.0.0,
like that option would be coming inside there, okay.
So like as you can see here, so add IP address, current IP address is not added,
you will not be able to connect to database from this address.
So add this and now your current IP is working successfully.
So this is, so now if you just control S, save again, it will start again.
And you can see that MongoDB is connected successfully and service running on port 5000.
So here is some catch and here is something that you might need to debug.
So I told you beforehand, so you guys don't need to panic and find the solutions in the stack overflow.
So now go in this tool.
Now as you can see in that post request has been passed in the JSON format and here in the curly braces.
Use the name email and password.
We're going to send this, it is taking some time.
Okay, so some small small bugs happens like we are going to miss some type one all.
So I try to test it, so it's working correctly.
So the problem was that in app.js I miss this braces, okay, open braces.
So just add this one and it will be working fine.
So now go here and when you send this, so you can see that our email username password.
And as you can see, why BigRip.js was used, you know, why like this, this is a way, extremely
big string format of random combination of some characters and special characters.
So as you can see, that's why we had used BigRip.js.
If we haven't used BigRip.js earlier and then in that case, it would be invisible.
So as you can see here, like profile pick email username, whatever it is, it's present
at timestamps as I've already told you, like I had created an updated it.
So that is the work of timestamps, okay.
So I hope you understand everything about this, like how to test a particular API and
how to implement just an update can and all.
So see you in the next video.